Guide to the Nate Brown Western Sound Archive Collection ARS.0124
Archive of Recorded Sound
Nate Brown Western Sound Archive Collection
1930-1981
ARS.0124
32 boxes: 1350 tapes [1190 7" reels; 131 10.5" reels; 19 5" reels; 13 3" reels]
Archive of Recorded Sound
The Nate Brown Western Sound Archive Collection consists of unpublished recordings on open reel tape of orchestral music from the 1940s through 1960s, with an emphasis on conductorship.
Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use. Contact the Archive for assistance.
Source
The Nate Brown Western Sound Archive Collection was donated to the Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound by Nate Brown in 1993.
Arrangement
The majority of tapes were numbered by Brown, and although the sequence contains many gaps, these comprise the main series. The remainder are listed in the following series: D prefix [dubs] -– RN/RM prefix [unknown prefrix] -– 3 prefix [3” reels] -– 4 prefix [4" reels] -– 5 prefix [5" reels] –- 10 prefix [10.5" reels] –- unnumbered tapes.
Scope and Contents
The Nate Brown Western Sound Archive Collection consists of unpublished recordings on open reel tape of orchestral music from the 1940s through 1960s, with an emphasis on conductorship. Brown's lifelong project was the non-profit Western Sound Archive, which in addition to these tapes also included original LPs, 78s, transcriptions and instantaneous discs (most of which are also now part of the Archive of Recorded Sound). The WSA can be differentiated from many other large private collections by Brown's willingness to share the material, mostly by trading on a tape for tape basis with other collectors, which in turn resulted in making still more recordings available. As the Archive itself put it, "all material in this listing is of a noncommercial nature unless otherwise indicated, and is available for exchange to private collectors and institutions only." Accordingly, there is an incredible variety here, and although there are few unique recordings, it is very likely that most of these recordings are not in general circulation or are not currently in-print commercially.
Sources for recordings are acknowledged on some tapes, among them William Malloch, Fred Maroth, Steve Smolian, I.J. Fung, and Richard Finnie. The worldwide collecting community exchanged their local recordings, collection lists and want lists, and in some cases even recorded their voices in greetings and commentary. Some tapes suggest that the donor may have done the recording themselves. However, the majority of tapes are air checks and off-air recordings, and some dates listed may be from later broadcasts. Many of these air checks are domestic rebroadcasts from international festivals (especially from Berkeley station KPFA), as well as from the BBC, Standard Hour, Radio Moscow, RAI, and others. A few recordings (such as some from Radio Nederland and the Broadcasting Foundation of America) are official broadcast tapes rather than dubs.
While the collection is primarily instrumental music, there are some vocal and choral works included. In addition to performances, there are also rehearsals, lectures and the occasional interview (many probably intermission filler from broadcasts). More often than not, more than one work or performance has been recorded on one tape. Movements are also split among tapes, and works are not always complete. As the tapes came from so many sources, there are many different recording, dubbing, and metadata standards at work. In many cases, notes, programs, and correspondence are enclosed with the tapes. There are also notes from Brown, i.e. "squeals, use tape no. 444." Some recordings were used for reissues on Maroth's Music and Arts label, and there are production notes from them on some tape boxes.
With a collection this size, selecting a few representative recordings is a tall order; however, the Western Sound Archive was particularly strong in the following areas: conductors such as Walter, Szell, Furtwangler, Klemperer, Mengelberg, Busch, Rosbaud, Boult, Goldberg, Ormandy, Mitropoulos, and Beecham; soloists such as Rostropovich, Michelangeli, Gould, Hofmann, Schnabel, and Landowska, and orchestras including the New York Philharmonic, Cleveland Orchestra, Vienna Philharmonic, Berlin Philharmonic, London Philharmonic, Royal Philharmonic, Los Angeles Philharmonic (including the Hollywood Bowl), BBC Symphony, NBC Symphony, Amsterdam Concertgebouw, Netherlands Chamber Orchestra, RAI Symphonic Orchestra of Rome, Turin, and Milan, San Francisco Symphony, Boston Symphony, and the Philadelphia Orchestra. There are recordings from music festivals in Holland, Vienna, Aldeburgh, Edinburgh, Salzburg, Budapest, and Prague, among others.
Indexing Terms
Brown, Nathan E.; Western Sound Archive.; Instrumental music; Orchestral music; Radio programs
- D prefix (dubs)
  Scope and Contents
  The "D" series are all dubs, many from rare and foreign-issued shellac 78s. Some appear to be copied from masters rather than commercial releases ( (a few say “sub-master” on the tape box), as well as from tests and private/custom pressings. There are also copies in the regular numbered section.
  - D-2. Fritz Busch Conducts I, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-3. Heger, Berlin Staatsoper. Atterberg, Symphony No.4 Gramophone Masterplate, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-4. Kleiber. Berlin Philharmonic, Schubert 8th; Belgian National Orchestra, Beethoven 2nd [from Telefunken, Ultrafon 78s], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-5. Treasury of 78s, KPFK, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-10. Pfitzner Conducts Beethoven. Deutsche Gramophone Private Issue 642015, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-11. Kreisler, BSOO. Beethoven, Violin Concerto, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-12. Busch, Haydn Symphony No. 100 [Columbia M-189], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-13. Casals. Dvorak, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-14. Casals. Boccherini, Elgar, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-17. Austrian Symphony, Gerard Poulet [Remington LPs R-199-125/131], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-18. Fischer, Dresen Opera. Beethoven, Concerto No. 5 [Electrola DB 5511/5], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-22. Fiedler, BSO. McDonald, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-25. LP Records, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
  - D-24. Hans Rosbaud Conducts [Mercury, DGG LPs], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-27. Orchestre National de la Radiodiffusion Francaise [Vox PL-8100], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-28. Susskind, Philharmonia Orchestra, Solomon [HMV 78s]; Davis, Sinfonia of London, Goossens [WRC T59], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-29. De Sabata, EIAR Orchestra [Decca 78s], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-30. Oscar Fried. Royal Philharmonic [Columbia M-119]; Berlin Philharmonic [Brunswick 90165/6], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-32. [contents crossed out], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-34. Busch Chamber Players, Serkin. Bach, Brandenberg Concertos 4-6, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-35. Busch Chamber Players. Bach, Suites for Orchestra 3 and 4 [Victor M-332], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-36. Busch Chamber Players, Moyse. Bach, Suites for Orchestra 1 and 2 [Victor M-332], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-37. Busch Chamber Players. Bach, Brandenberg Concertos 1-4, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-38. Weingartner, Vienna Philharmonic. Beethoven Symphony No. 3 [Columbia M-285], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-39. Weingartner. Royul Philharmonic [Columbia M-63]; London Philharmonic [Columbia X-133], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-41. Susskind, Philharmonia, Goldberg [Parlophone 78s], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-42. Weingartner, RPO [Columbnia M-126]; Beecham, RPO [Columbia Mod.Mus 2], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-43. Stokowski, Philadelphia Orchestra [Victor 2060/1]; Weisman, Berlin State Opera Orchestra [Parlophone E 11113/4], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-44. Markovitch, Belgian National Orchestra [HMV DB-5069/71]; Zsolt, Budapest Conservatory Orchestra [HMV AN-454]; Schurcht, La Scala Orchestra [HMV DB 5401/2], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-46. Bruckner Scherzi [Victor, Gramophone 78s]; Sibelius [Gramophone, Columbia 78s], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-48. Grainger, Colonial Song. Atwater, Sanchez, Grainger [Columbia 2066-M], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-50. Strauss, Berlin State Opera Orchestra [Polydor, Brunswick 78s], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-51. Strauss, Berlin State Opera Orchestra [Columbia, Gramophone 78s], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-64. Weingartner. The Tempest [Colmbia]; Wagner, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-66. Pretzner [Brunswick 78s]; Kleiber [Ultraphone, HMV, Victor 78s]; Fiedler [Brunswick 78s], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-79. Walter, NYPSO. Beethoven, Eroica; Barber #1 [Columbia 33 rpm acetates], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-80. Walter, NYPSO. Beethoven, Eroica, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-81. Walter rehearsals [Columbia W2-3], 1958; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - D-82. Walyer, NYPSO. Barber #1 [Columbia], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-84. Famous Soloists [Victor, Remington], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-85. Menuhins. Enesco [HMV Fr. DB 2739/41]; Lekev [HMV Fr. DB 3492/5], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-90. Schnabel. Schubert, 1937-10; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-92. Schnabel [correspondence enclosed], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-93. Paray. Pro Musica Orchestra. Beethoven [Polydor 647]; Lamoureaux Orchestra, Casadesus. Mozart [Vox 650], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-94. Cantelli, La Scala Orchestra. Tchaikovsky #5 [HMV 9583/7], 1 7" open reel tape folders (Audio 3)
  - D-95. Paray, Detroit Symphony. Paray, Mass [Sterodisc SR90128], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-96. Cologne Orchestra Concerts, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-97. Cologne Orchestra Concerts, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-99. Weingartner, London Symphony, London Philharmonic. Brahms Symphonies, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-99 (2). Furtwangler, BPO [Brunswick, Polydor], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-99 (3). Walter, BSOP. Tchaikovsky 6th [Polydor], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-100. Stokowski. Prokofieff, Romeo and Juliet [RCA-Victor DCS-18], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-101. Mengelberg, NYPSO. Beethoven #1 [Victort M-73]; Coates. Wagner [Victor], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-102. Walter, Royal Philharmonic. Wagner [Columbia, Eng. Columbia], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-102 (2). Hanson, Eastman Philharmonia [Mercury SR-90357] [also numbered 2613], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 23)
  - D-103. Walter, NYPSO. Mozart #35. 1953 CBS Program [XLP 15234], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-104. Stokowski, Philadelphia Orchestra. Wagner [Victor M-530], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-105. Bruno Walter Demo Record 2. Sub-Master [Columbia XLP 15233], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-105 (2). Stokowski, NBC Symphony [RCA LM-1830], 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 32)
  - D-106. Rosza Conducts his Music [Vox LP PL-7690], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-107. Michelangeli [Telefunken], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-108. Conductart LPs, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-108 (2). Myra Hess, Piano. Schubert [Columbia M-87], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-10[9?]. Walter, Acoustics [Polydor], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-111. World's Greatest Music Series [Music Appreciation Records], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-183. Walter, LPO. Schumann, 4th, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - D-221. [contents crossed out], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
- RN/RM prefix
  - RM 26, RM 28. Karl Kritz, Syracuse Symphony Orchestra. Broadcast transcriptions, 1968; 2 10.5" open reel tapes (Audio 1)
  - RN 1. Holland Festival. Hattink, Concertgebouw [Radio Nederland 245.827], 1968-06-27; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 24)
  - RN 2. Holland Festival. Hattink, Concertgebouw [Radio Nederland 245.827], 1968-06-27; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 24)
  - RN 3. Holland Festival. Hattink, Concertgebouw [Radio Nederland 262.813], 1969-06-19; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 24)
  - RN 4. Holland Festival. Hattink, Concertgebouw [Radio Nederland 262.813], 1969-06-19; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 24)
  - RN 5. Holland Festival. Beinum, Netherlands Chamber Orchestra [Radio Nederland], 1969-07-19; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 24)
  - RN 6. Holland Festival. Iwaki, Rotterdam Philharmonic [Radio Nederland 245.521], 1968-06-19; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 24)
  - RN 7-11. Holland Festival, 1968-1969; 6 7" open reel tapes (Audio 1)
- 3 prefix (3" reels)
  - 3-1. Pasadena Symphony, Lott. Strauss, Horn Concerto No.2, 1965-02-13; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 32)
  - 3-2. Los Angeles Philharmonic, 1964-12-17; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 32)
  - 3-3. Los Angeles Philharmonic, 1964-12-31; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 32)
  - 3-4. Los Angeles Philharmonic, 1965-01-07; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 32)
  - 3-5. Los Angeles Philharmonic, 1965-01-14; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 32)
  - 3-6. Kubelik, Los Angeles Philharmonic. Schubert, Symphony No.8; Debussy, Nocturnes; Dvorak, Symphony no.4, 1965-01-21; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 32)
  - 3-7. Wallenstein, Los Angeles Philharmonic, Janis. Schumann, Manfred Overture; Strauss, Til Eulenspiegel; Prokofiev, Concerto No.3; Beethoven, Symphony No.7, 1965-01-28; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 32)
  - 3-8. Los Angeles Philharmonic, 1965-02-04; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 32)
  - 3-8. Los Angeles Philharmonic, 1965-02-11; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 32)
  - 3-11. Van Otterloo, Hague Philharmonic. Haydn, Symphony no.8; Hindemith, Mathis; Ravel, Daphnis No.2; Strauss, Don Juan, 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 32)
  - 3-11. Heifetz, Piatigorsky. Vivaldi, Bach, Toch, Mendelssohn, 1965-04-04; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 32)
- 4 prefix (4" reels)
  - 4-6. Swarowksy, LA Philharmonic. Mahler, Third, 1965-02-19; 1 open reel tape (4" reel) (Audio 32)
- 5 prefix (5" reels)
  - 5-6. Beinum, ACO, Casadesus. Ravel, Concerto in D Major, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 32)
- 10 prefix (10.5" reels)
  - 10-A. Elgar Recordings, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 24)
  - 10-7. Katims, Philadelphia Orchestra 11/3/63; Steinberg, Philadelphia Orchestra 11/10/63, 1963-11; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 24)
  - 10-8. Schnabel, Piano. Beethoven, Weber, Schumann, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 24)
  - 10-14. Smith, Philadelphia Orchestra, Luuisi. Mozart, Strauss, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 24)
  - 10-36. Monteux, Boston Symphony Orchestra. Berkshire Festival 8/2/64; Steinberg, New York Philharmonic 5/23/65, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 24)
  - 10-39. Steinberg, New York Philharmonic. Schubert, Kirchner, Berlioz; Mehta, Los Angeles Philharmonic. Beethoven, Foss, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 24)
  - 10-40. Davis, London Symphony Orchestra and Chorus. Berlioz, L'Entrance Du Christ. Edinburgh 1964; Munch, Milhaud, Radiodiffusion Television Francaised Orchestra. Milhaud, Beethoven, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 24)
  - 10-41. Villa-Lobos, Janssen Symphony Orchestra. Philharmonic Auditorium, Los Angeles, 1944; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 24)
  - 10-42. Munch, RTF Orchestra, Horne. Faure, Berlioz, Roussel. Edinburgh; Munch, Boston Symphony. Mozart, Mendelssohn, Honneger, Ravel 4/10/65, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 25)
  - 10-44. Stokowski, Philadelphia Orchestra. Schoenberg [Victor M-127]; Stravinsky Piano Rolls, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 25)
  - 10-45. Munch, Radiodiffusion Television Orchestra. Sibelius Festival, 1964-06; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 25)
  - 10-46. Markevitch, Orchestra National De La Radiodiffusione-Television Francaise. Bordeaux Festival 1964; Barbirolli, Boston Symphony Orchestra. Idyllwild Festival 1963, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 25)
  - 10-60. Handel, Semele. Gottingen Hadel Festival 1966 part 2; Bernstein, NY Philharmonic, Kempff. Beethoven, Piano Concerto No.3 in C 10/29/66; Klemperer, VPO. Purcell, Fairie Queen, Orchestral Suite. Salzburg Festival 8/24/47, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 25)
  - 10-63. Munch, Boston Symphony, Richter. Beethoven, First Piano Concerto; Brahms, Second Piano Concerto, 1960; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 25)
  - 10-65. Furtwangler 1, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 25)
  - 10-68. Riou, Limburg Symphony Orchestra. Beethoven, Dvorak [Radio Nederland 224998/2], 1 10.5" open reel tape folders (Audio 32)
  - 10-70. Kleiber, Vienna Philharmonic [London LL632/33], 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 25)
  - 10-73. Celibidache, RAI (Turin). Franck 1962; Celibidache, Radio Koln. Brahms; Furtwangler, Scala. Wagner 1950; Klemperer, Vienna Philharmonic. Mahler 1968; Kleiber, NBC. Beethoven 1/10/48, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 25)
  - 10-74. Goldberg, Netherlands Chamber Orchestra. Bach, Badings, Britten [Radio Nederland 247.908/3-8], 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 25)
  - 10-75. Pollini. Caracciolo, RAI Milano 6/15/66; Ycaglia, RAI Torino 11/27/59; Mitropoulos, Concertgebouw, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 25)
  - 10-84. Koldofsky, CBC Symphony, Landowska. CBL, Toronto. CBC, 1943-04-25; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 25)
  - 10-86. Goldberg, Cleveland Orchestra. Bach, Mozart, Schubert, Hindemith, 1969-01; 1 10.5" open reel tape folders (Audio 32)
  - 10-88. Rosbaud, SWF Orchestra. Beethoven 6/19-25/59; Brahms 12/17-21/62; Bruckner 12/17-22/60; Haydn 10/26/57, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 25)
  - 10-90. Mengelberg, Concertgebouw [Philips, JPN FL-5569/70]; [Philips ENG GL-5806]; ;Telefunken JPN NH 5245], 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 25)
  - 10-91. Mengelberg, Concertgebouw. Beethoven, Symphony No.7; Schubert, Symphony No.8; Brahms, Symphony No.1, 1939-1940; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 25)
  - 10-99. Hollywood Bowl. Mahler, Symphony No.8, 1948-07-29; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 25)
  - 10-102. Busch, NY Philharmonic. Human Rights Day Concert, 1950-12-10; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 10-103. Barshai, Moscow Chamber Orchestra, Vishnevskaya, Reshetin. Moscow Conservatory, 1969-10; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 10-105. Danish Music [Radio Denmark transcriptions], 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 10-111. Szell, Boulez, Cleveland Orchestra Majeske, Barenboim. 3/26/70; 3/5/70. WCLV [programs enclosed], 1970-03; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 10-115. Boulez at Blossom Music Center. Raskin, Rose. WCLV, 1969-07; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 117. Prausnitz, Syracuse Symphony. Mahler, Symphony No.6 in A Minor 12/1971; Krasner, Syracuse Symphony, Kritz. Berg, Violin Concerto 1/5/68, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 10-124. Walter, Philharmonic-Symphony Orchestra of New York. Bruckner, Symphony No.9 in D-minor, 1953-12-27; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 10-125. Standard Hour Programs 3/10/46; 4/23/50, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 10-129. Downes, Bournemouth Symphony, Rostropovich, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 10-137. Kritz, Syracuse Symphony. Schmidt, Symphony No.2. Rehearsal, 1969-12-10; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 30)
  - 140. Boulez, Levine, NY Philharmonic. 1975-76; Cleveland Orchestra 1985 Marathon Playback WCLV. Rudell, Sills 8/7/76; Szell, Stern, Rose, Istomin 4/14/66 [etc.], 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 148. Kritz, Syracuse Symphony. Schumann, Dvorak, Bruckner [RM-30 Program 30], 1969; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 149. Kritz, Syracuse Symphony, Ludgin. Wagner 1-2/69; Kritz, Syracuse Symphony. Williams 11/1/69, 1969; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 152. Kritz, Syracuse Symphony. Beethoven, Egmont Overture; Elgar, Enigma Variations; Dvorak, Cello Concerto in B-minor [RM-3 Program 3], 1966; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 154. Kritz, Syracuse Symphony, Fleisher. Ravel, Britten 3/14-15/69; Kritz, Syracuse Symphony, Starker. Hindemith 2/23-24/68, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 155. Kritz, Syracuse Symphony. Strauss. Death and Transfiguration, 1966-12; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 156. Kritz, Syracuse Symphony. Alfven, Symphony No.4 in C Minor, 1966-11; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 157. Kritz, Syracuse Symphony. Schmidt, Symphony No.2 in E Flat [RM-12 Program 12 Part 2], 1969-12-11; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 158. Kritz, Syracuse Symphony, Schauler, Ludgin. Strauss, Wagner 1/31 - 2/1/69, 1969; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 178. Kritz, Druba, SUNY Crane Chorus, Chase, Mallette, Greer. Orff, Carmina Burana 4/22-23/66, 1966-04; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 179. Kritz, Syracuse Symphony, Rosand. Tchaikovsky 3/17-18/67; Kritz, Syracuse Symphony, Macarthur. Martinu 5/12/67; Kritz, Syracuse Symphony. Von Weber 4/6/68, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 26)
  - 180. Kritz, Syracuse Symphony, Doktor. Porter, Violin Concerto; Rolla, Viola Concerto 12/10-11/65; Kritz, Syracuse Symphony, Contiguglia. Serley, Double Piano Concerto 11/12-13/1965; Kritz, Syracuse Symphony. Kodaly, Summer Evening 2/13-15/69, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 181. Kritz, Syracuse Symphony, Frank. Mozart, Piano Concerto No. 25 in C K.503 12/16-17/66; Kritz, Syracuse Symphony, Molin. Serley, Piano Concertino 3 x 3. 1/14/67, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 184. Barbirolli, Boston Symphony. Purcell, Haydn, Elgar, 1964-11-07; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 185. Barbirolli, Boston Symphony. Berlioz, Delius, Vaughan Williams, 1964-10-30; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 186. Brediceanu, Syracuse Symphony. Strauss, Alpine Symphony 10/8-10/70, 1970-10; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 187. Leinsdorf, Cleveland Orchestra, Rostropovich. Pension Fund Concert 1/17/72; Boulez, Cleveland Orchestra. Wolf Trap 1/71, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 191. Ceccato, Cleveland Orchestra, Firkusny. Rossini, Mendelssohn, Rachmaninoff, 1971-10; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 194. Ceccato, Cleveland Orchestra. 54th Season, 25th and 26th programs [programs enclosed], 1971-19172; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 10-204. Weingartner, London Philharmonic. Beethoven, Symphony No.5; Weingartner, Royal Philharmonic. Beethoven, Symphony No.6, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 10-204 (2). Weingartner, Vienna Philharmonic, Petri. Beethoven, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 10-212. Knappertsbusch. Beethoven, Symphony No.8. NDR, Hamburg Music Hall, 1960-03-14; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 10-213. Beecham, Symphony of the Air. Beethoven, 1957-01-27; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 10-214. Beecham, Symphony of the Air. Brahms, 1957-01-23; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 10-215. Beecham, Symphony of the Air. Grieg, Berlioz, Strauss, 1957-01; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 10-216. Wagner, Covent Garden 1936-37 [crossed out], 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 10-226. Walter, NY Philharmonic. Mahler, Das Lied 2/22/53; Brahms, Tragic Overture 3/16/52, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 10-226A. Walter, NY Philharmonic. Vaughn Williams; Mahler, 1953-02-22; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 226A. Walter, NY Philharmonic. Brahms, 1952-03-16; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 10-231. Szell, Philharmonic-Symphony Orchestra of New York. Bruckner, Symphony No.8 in C Minor. WDRC, 1950-12-24; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 10-233. Radio Nederland Concert No.94. De Waart, Rotterdam Philharmonic, Grumiaux [Radio Nederland 246.765], 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 27)
  - 10-234. Walter, NY Philharmonic. Mozart, 1956-03-04; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 28)
  - 10-251. Goldberg, Netherlands Chamber Orchestra. Holland Festival, 1973-07-02; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 28)
  - 10-257. Holland Festival. Martinon, Hague Philharmonic 6/26/74; Fournet, Amsterdam Concertgebouw 6/24/74, 1974; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 28)
  - 10-258. Beecham, Messiah pt.1 [See D-98 for Part 2], 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 28)
  - 10-259. Weingartner, RPO. Beethoven [Columbia Set 153]; Weingartner, LSO [Columbia 78s], 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 28)